Philip Robinson

Portland, OR 97219

pmoss.robinson+res@gmail.com 206.377.9747

http://probinso.dyn-o-saur.com

Personal Statement

I am a graduate student at Oregon Health and Sciences University. After completing my BS at Western Washington University, and my 4 years industry expirience, I have developed strong interests in cryptography, statistical computing, and languages. I am a very quick study, as I have adopted a new programming language or tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. My interest in teaching and writing has granted me strong communication skills, and solid background.

Language Experience :

* Python Julia Scala, Figaro Perl Ada R C, C++ $\mathbb{E}T_{\mathbb{F}}X$

Education

Oregon Health Science University

CSLU

Graduate Student 2016 - present

Courses :

Machine Learning Information Retrieval Computing Ethics

Statistical Methods Univariate Statistical Analysis Analysis of Sequences

Western Washington University

Computer Science

Computer Science BS Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

Courses :

Unix Software Development Windows Software Development Analysis of Algorithms Linear/Non-Linear Data Structures Formal Languages/Automata Programming Languages Concurrent Programming Computer Organization I/II

Electives :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Natural Language Processing Functional Programming

Computer Graphics Elementary Real Analysis Linear Algebra I/II Abstract Algebra

Work Experience

Independent C&W Energy

- Contractor/Consultant

Nov. 2015 - present

Authored educational material on light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Light classification engine, custom photo image processing tools, and mathematical models Developed a memoizing database-interface for caching computationally expensive operations ComScore June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis

June 2016 PDXCodeGuild

Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Melinae March 2016 Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable workflow for remote company

Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++

- Research Engineer Galois Inc.

April 2014 - Dec 2015 Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track

Developed technologies and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker

EMC² Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Languages Used : C, C++, Python, SQLite

Computer Science Dept. - Mentors Program Director/Mentor Sept. 2009 - March 2012

Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors Ran student/faculty meetings to project future program responsibilities Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, and tools for automatic report generation

Languages Used : Ada, C++, Scheme, R

Neato Projects

Gradient Descent on Arbitrary Degree Polynomials Julia R, caret Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor Sensor Systems and Light Pollution Course aws, sklearn, scipy, PonyORM, Python Dating a Band - Lyrics Release Date Classifier javascript, Python Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Python Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Erlang, Sagemath Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions R, Perl AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Ada TwixT AI Agent and UI Java Fractal Art Generator & Image Manipulation Program C#